Alright then gang, we have reached the end of the series and I really hope you've enjoyed it and maybe you're seeing the benefit of adding Claude code into your own development workflow now.I do want to end the course on a few final thoughts, words of caution and just a little bit of advice for using Claude code and also some shortcuts and tips near the end of the video as well.So first of all, and I think I've stressed this throughout the videos quite a lot already, always check the code yourself.
好的，各位，我們已經來到了系列的尾聲，真心希望你們都享受這個課程， 也許現在你開始看到將 Claude Code 加入自己開發工作流程的好處了。 我想以幾個最後的想法、一些注意事項和使用建議來結束這門課程， 影片後半段也會介紹一些快捷鍵和技巧。 首先，我想我在影片中已經多次強調過了：一定要自己檢查程式碼。
AI can make mistakes sometimes, so be sure it's correct.Don't automatically assume everything it does is right.Checking the code yourself also helps to keep you in the loop, understand your code base, and know how everything is fitting together.And that's going to really help in the future if you do ever need to do some manual debugging or code edits.Secondly, context is key when you're using any kind of AI tool like Claude Code.
AI 有時會犯錯，所以要確保它是正確的，不要自動假設它所做的一切都是對的。 自己檢查程式碼也能幫助你保持在迴圈中、了解你的程式碼庫， 並知道一切是如何組合在一起的。 如果你以後真的需要進行手動除錯或程式碼編輯，這將非常有幫助。 其次，當你使用 Claude Code 這樣的 AI 工具時，上下文至關重要。
And I don't just mean bombard the model with context about everything.I mean, be smart about your context.Keep it focused, concise where you can, and keep the context history lean where possible to keep the model on track.Don't be afraid to clear the context or start a new session if it ever gets bloated.And as a rule of thumb, I tend to clear the context and start over whenever I work on a new feature or task.And finally, I would say don't rely on AI to do everything for you.
我的意思不是要向模型灌輸大量上下文。 我的意思是要聰明地管理上下文：盡量保持專注和簡潔， 並在可能的情況下讓上下文歷史保持精簡，讓模型保持在正軌上。 如果上下文變得臃腫，不要害怕清除它或開始新的作業階段。 一個經驗法則是，每當我處理新功能或任務時，我都會清除上下文並重新開始。 最後，我想說的是：不要依賴 AI 為你做所有事情。
Yes, it can be good as a coding assistant and loads more things.I'd probably compare it to maybe having a junior or even a mid-level developer working alongside you.But if you use it too often and rely on it for every single problem, it's going to turn you into a lazy programmer who might not learn new skills and even forget current ones because you're not using them.And on that same note, I would also say this.A lot of coders right now think AI is going to replace them.And I think that's not true for several reasons right now.
是的，它作為程式設計助手以及更多用途上可以很有用。 我可能會把它比作有一個初級甚至中級開發者在你身旁工作。 但如果你使用它太頻繁，依賴它解決每一個問題， 它會讓你變成一個懶惰的程式設計師， 可能無法學到新技能，甚至因為不使用而忘掉現有的技能。 同樣地，我還想說這個：現在很多開發者認為 AI 會取代他們。 我認為目前這是不正確的，有幾個原因。
I do think the way we code will be different and AI will certainly play a big role in whatever the landscape looks like in the future.But I don't think, at least not yet, it's in any position to completely replace web developers.And in fact, I think AI just brings more opportunities to developers.Think of all the new types of applications and programs that are being developed that incorporate AI.MCP servers, agents, custom AI integrations, even developing sites and APIs with AI usage and security in mind.
我確實認為我們撰寫程式碼的方式將會不同， AI 肯定會在未來的格局中扮演重要角色。 但我認為，至少目前，AI 還沒有完全取代網頁開發者的能力。 事實上，我認為 AI 只是為開發者帶來了更多機會。 想想那些正在開發的整合 AI 的新型應用程式： MCP 伺服器、代理、自訂 AI 整合， 甚至以 AI 使用和安全性為考量來開發網站和 API。
All those things are now being developed, and I think that brings a whole new level of opportunity for web developers to specialize in.I also think because we will be getting a whole swathe of applications built almost entirely using AI, unfortunately, there's still going to be a big call for coders who can go into the weeds, understand theand manually work on it.And for all these reasons, I think learning to code is arguably more important now than it was before.Anyway, now my part in wisdom is out of the way.
所有這些事情現在都在被開發，我認為這為網頁開發者帶來了全新層次的專業化機會。 我也認為，因為我們將迎來大量幾乎完全使用 AI 建立的應用程式， 可惜的是，仍然會有大量對能夠深入研究、理解並手動處理程式碼的開發者的需求。 基於所有這些原因，我認為學習撰寫程式碼在現在比以往更為重要。 好了，我的人生哲學說完了。
Let's end on a few shortcuts that we can use within Claude Code to make life working with it a little bit easier.Alright, so first of all, you can use the up and down arrow keys to cycle through previous prompts to see them if you want to send a previous prompt again.There's another one.If you press escape, then you can clear out the chat.Also, if youinto something say we use a tool like or not tool sorry a command like mcp you can always press escape to exit out of these windows and it goes back to the chat.
讓我們以一些在 Claude Code 中可以使用的快捷鍵來結束，讓使用體驗更輕鬆一些。 好的，首先，你可以使用上下方向鍵來循環瀏覽先前的提示詞， 如果你想再次發送之前的提示詞。 還有一個：如果你按 Escape，可以清除聊天輸入框的內容。 另外，如果你進入某個畫面，比如使用了像 /mcp 這樣的指令， 你隨時可以按 Escape 退出這些視窗，回到聊天介面。
You can also use the question mark to go into bash mode so now you can run bash commands so for example I could say git status and it's going to run that command for us exactly so it's on branch main and
你也可以使用問號（?）進入 Bash 模式，這樣你就可以執行 Bash 指令了。 例如，我可以輸入 git status，它就會為我執行那個指令。 就是這樣，顯示我在 main 分支上，以及...
You can double escape.I think I might have shown this in a previous lesson, but you can double escape to go to previous sections of the chats.I could go back to this one if I wanted to, or this one, and it's going to take me back to that point in the chat, and it's going to clear out any history beyond that.If I press double escape now, then you can see there's no chats after this current one.Down here at the bottom, there is this little hint here that says question mark for shortcuts.
你可以按兩下 Escape。 我想我可能在之前的課程中展示過這個，但你可以按兩下 Escape 回到聊天的先前部分。 我可以回到這個，或者這個，它會把我帶回聊天中的那個點，並清除之後的所有歷史記錄。 如果我現在按兩下 Escape，你可以看到這個之後沒有更多聊天記錄了。 下方這裡有一個小提示，說按問號查看快捷鍵。
If I press question mark, you're going to see some of those shortcuts that we've seen as well.So this was the bash mode I just showed you, this for tools, this for file paths for adding context, and this to memorize something inside the Claude.md file.Okay then my friends, so that just about wraps it up.If you enjoyed this series, please don't forget to give the videos a thumbs up and subscribe to the channel.Maybe share the videos if you're feeling kind as well.
如果我按問號，你會看到我們之前看過的一些快捷鍵。 這個是我剛才展示的 Bash 模式，這個是工具， 這個是新增上下文的檔案路徑，這個是在 CLAUDE.md 檔案中記憶某些內容。 好了，朋友們，這差不多就到這裡了。 如果你喜歡這個系列，請別忘了給影片點個讚並訂閱頻道，如果你覺得不錯也可以分享給別人。
And please let me know in the comments if you would like more Claude code courses in the future.I have debated making a whole big masterclass about Claude code, where we use it to help build an entire application from scratch.So let me know if that's something you would like to see in the future.Anyway, thanks for watching, and I'm going to see you all in the next series.So then my friends, I really, really hope you enjoyed this series and you learned something along the way.If you did, please, please, please don't forget to share, subscribe and like.
請在留言中告訴我，你未來是否希望看到更多 Claude Code 課程。 我一直在考慮製作一個關於 Claude Code 的大型大師課， 我們用它從零開始協助建立一個完整的應用程式。 所以讓我知道這是否是你未來想看到的內容。 無論如何，感謝觀看，我們下個系列再見。 朋友們，我真的真的希望你們喜歡這個系列，並在過程中學到了一些東西。 如果有的話，請一定不要忘記分享、訂閱和點讚。
That really means a lot.And if you want to access all of my YouTube courses without adverts, also get access to premium courses and early access courses as well, you can do at netninja.dev.You can sign up for Net Ninja Pro, which is just $9 a month and also half price for the first month with this promo code right here.And for that, like I said,Instead, you get access to every course without adverts, without YouTube adverts.You also get access to exclusive courses not found anywhere else.
這真的對我意義重大。 如果你想存取我所有的 YouTube 課程且無廣告，也想獲得付費課程和提早存取課程的權限， 你可以前往 netninja.dev，報名 Net Ninja Pro，每月只需 9 美元， 第一個月還有這裡的促銷碼可享半價優惠。 就像我說的，你可以無廣告地存取所有課程， 還可以存取在其他地方找不到的獨家課程。
You get access to my premium courses on Udemy and also early access to all of my YouTube courses as well.So the link to this page to sign up is going to be down below.Again, I really hope you enjoyed this series and I'm going to see you in the very next one.
你可以存取我在 Udemy 上的付費課程，也可以提早存取我所有的 YouTube 課程。 報名頁面的連結將在下方。再次希望你喜歡這個系列，我們下個系列見。
.
（片尾）
..........
（片尾音樂）